Finding Aid to the Education collection SSC.MS.00446
Sophia Smith Collection
- WOMEN'S STUDIES
  - Associations, programs, research centers, and conferences [see also Women?s Liberation Collection?Organizations, etc.] (Box 23)
    - Programs and research centers ? United States (Box 24)
      - San Jose State University, undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Sarah Lawrence College, 1973; undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
      - Southwest Institute for Research on Women, 1987-92 (Box 28, Folder 17)
      - Spelman College, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Stanford University, 1970-84 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - State Universities of New York (S.U.N.Y.), 1970; undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Trinity College, 1989-91 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - University of (Box 28)
        - Alabama, 1974-87; undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
        - Arizona, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 23)
        - Cincinnati, 1980-91 (Box 28, Folder 24)
        - Connecticut, 1976-92 (Box 28, Folder 25)
        - Hawaii, 1985-92 (Box 28, Folder 26)
        - Illinois, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 1)
        - Maine, 1975; 1986 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - Maryland, 1978-79; undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
        - Massachusetts, Boston, 1972-86 (Box 29, Folder 4)
        - Minnesota (Box 29)
          - Center for Advanced Feminist Studies, 1986-92 (Box 29, Folder 5)
          - Evaluation of course on women, 1970s (Box 29, Folder 6)
        - Mississippi, 1986-92 (Box 29, Folder 7)
        - Missouri, 1978-80 (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - New Mexico, 1974-92 (Box 29, Folder 9)
        - Oregon, 1978-80 (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - Pittsburgh, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - Rhode Island, 1988-92; undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
        - Utah, 1977-78; 1984 (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - Washington, 1971; undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
        - Wisconsin (Box 29)
          - General, 1973-82 (Box 29, Folder 15)
          - Milwaukee Women Yesterday and Milwaukee Women Today, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Vanderbilt University, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Wellesley College Center for Research on Women, 1976-82; undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Wesleyan University, 1971; undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Women?s Institute, undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - San Diego State University Socialist Feminist Women Studies Program (Box 29)
        - History of the program by Nan Wiegersma, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 1)
        - Statement of purpose, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - Curriculum proposals, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - Syllabi, 1970; undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
        - Newsletters, 1970-71; undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
        - Publication: La Verdad, Jul 1971 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - Pamphlets, 1973-74 (Box 30, Folder 7)
        - Articles and essays, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Women?s Research and Education Institute, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous programs and centers, 1970-86; undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Programs and research centers ? International (Box 31)
      - Canada (Box 31)
        - General, 1977; undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
        - L?Institut Simone de Beauvoir (Box 31)
          - General, 1979-80 (Box 31, Folder 4)
          - International Conference on Research and Teaching Related to Women, 1982 (Box 31)
            - General (Box 31, Folder 5)
            - Conference papers (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - England, 1976-77; undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Institute for Women?s Studies in the Arab World, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - International Institute of Women?s Studies, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Latin America, 1981-82; undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Study abroad opportunities, 1974-88 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Courses (Box 31)
        - Correspondence, 1970-71 (Box 31, Folder 12)
        - Proposals, 1969-72; undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
        - Listings and descriptions, 1970-82; undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
        - Syllabi, 1970-79; undated (Box 31, Folder 15)
        - Miscellaneous, 1970s-1983; undated (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Women?s Studies Programs in Public Schools, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Women?s History (Box 31)
      - Approaches to Women?s History: a Resource Book and Teaching Guide by Ann Chapman, American Historical Association, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Pamphlets, 1966-77 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Conference Group in Women?s History Newsletter, 1979; 1983 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Listing of courses and research on women?s history, 1970-1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Southern Association for Women Historians, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - ?A Syllabus in the History of Civilization with Special Emphasis on the Part Played by Women? by Elizabeth H. Day and Margaret A. Koch, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - ?Women at Work, Home and School,? Elementary Social Studies, National Women?s History Project, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Women?s history week, 1982-84 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Conferences (Box 32)
        - Berkshire Conference on the History of Women (Box 32)
          - General, 1974-83 (Box 32, Folder 9)
          - Scholarly paper, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 10)
        - National Archives Conference on Women?s History, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 11)
        - Recent Scholarship on the History of Women, 1980; 1983 (Box 32, Folder 12)
        - Upstate New York Women?s History Conference, 1978-82 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Conferences ? regional (Box 32)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Canada, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Midwest, 1971-77 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Northeast (Box 33)
        - General, 1969-79 (Box 33, Folder 4)
        - Smith-Smithsonian Conference on the Convention of Gender, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 5)
          - Conference papers, A-M (Box 33, Folder 6)
          - Conference papers, N-Z (Box 33, Folder 7)
        - SUNY, 1974 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - South, 1974-79 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - West, 1974-80 (Box 33, Folder 10)
- COUNTRIES AND REGIONS
  - Africa, 1927-61 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - The Asian Women's Institute, 1972-82 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Australia, 1965 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Austria, 1928-29 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Canada, 1871; 1954; 1962-77 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - China (Box 34)
    - Pamphlets, 1918-19; 1964 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - General, 1919-71 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Post War Planning Committee Report, undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - England [see separate box] (Box 34)
  - Finland, 1983 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - France, 1847; 1922-29; undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Germany, 1924-33; undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Hungary, 1913; 1929 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - India [see separate box] (Box 34)
  - International Education, 1954-76 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Iran: Damavand College, 1969; undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Ireland (Box 35)
    - Alexandra College, Dublin, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Belfast Ladies Industrial National School for Girls, 1852 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Japan [see separate box] (Box 35)
  - Korea (Box 35)
    - General, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - EWHA Woman's University; Helen Kim, President, 1929-66 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Seoul Women?s College, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Hansung Girls' Middle and High School, Seoul, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Sook Myung Girls' High School, Seoul, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Lebanon: Beirut College for Women, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Near East College Association, 1932; 1951 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Near East: Institute for Women's Studies in the Arab World, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Netherlands, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Norway, 1914 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Orient: Women's Union Christian Colleges, 1920-22 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Philippines (Box 36)
    - University of the Philippines, 1938 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Philippine Women's University, undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - "Higher Education of Women" (from Maria C. Peralto), 1959 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rico, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Russia: Sophie Satin, 1966; 1971 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Spain, 1910-42 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Sweden, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Switzerland: The College for Women in Geneva, undated (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Syria: American School for Girls, Damascus, Syria, 1925-39 [see also Pearce Family Papers] (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Turkey: American College for Girls, Istanbul, 1906-58 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - England (Box 36)
    - Magazine articles, 1858-1928 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Bedford College, London, 1882-1949 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1897-1952 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Hillcroft College, Surbiton, 1928; 1930 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Kings College, 1882 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - National Union of Women Teachers (Box 37)
      - Pamphlets, 1928-49 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Equal Pay Campaign, undated (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - North London Collegiate School for Girls, 1881 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Oxford (Box 37)
      - Association for the Education of Women, 1892-1956 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Somerville College, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Lady Margaret Hall, 1890-1916 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlets, 1810-1928 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Queen's College, 1882-83 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Teachers Training and Registration Society, 1880 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - University of London: pamphlets, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - Working Women's College, 1880-1923 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - India (Box 37)
    - General, 1910-61 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Adult education, 1910; 1913; undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Baroda University, 1950-58 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Delhi University, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Isabella Thorburn College, Lucknow, 1922-31 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Ministry of Education, Government of India, 1954-62 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Queen Mary's, New Delhi, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Shreemati Nathibai Damadher Thackersey Indian Women's University, 1927; 1931; undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Vidyodaya School, Madras, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Women's Christian College, Madras, 1916-20 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - All India Women's Conference on Education Reform, 1927-29 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Sakhow at Memorial Girls' School, Calcutta, 1916 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Japan (Box 38)
    - General, 1921-66 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Japan Women's University, Tokyo, 1963-84 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Michi Kawai: Biographical information, 1920-53 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Kindergartens, 1940; 1967 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Kobe College [SEE DeForest Papers and Smith College Archives] (Box 39)
    - National Women's Education Centre of Japan, 1983-2001 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Soshin Girls' School, Yokohawa (Sochia Jo Gakko), 1891-2002 (Box 39, Folder 6-7)
    - Tsuda College, Tokyo, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Woman's Christian College of Japan, Tokyo, 1926-61 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - United States (Box 39)
    - Higher education: Bibliography, 1897-1971 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1881-1973 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - American Council on Education, 1957-60 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - American Woman's Education Association, Circular, 1852 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Institute of Women's Professional Relations, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Ladies' Society for the Promotion of Education at the West, 1852 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Letter from Elmer Ellsworth Brown to Miss Gleason, 1897 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Magazine articles, 1855-80 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Pamphlets and articles (Box 40)
      - 1901-60 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - 1966-79, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Woman's Education Association of Boston, 1873-1907 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Unpublished papers, 1958, 1971, n.d (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - United States: Legislation (Box 40)
    - Federal laws and regulations prohibiting sex discrimination in educational institutions, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Legal Issues, 1979-80 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Title IX, 1973-80 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Women's Educational Equity Communications Network (Box 41)
      - Publications, 1978-undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Network News and Notes, 1978-80 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Women's Educational Equity Act (Box 41)
      - The Dissemination Center, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - Grant Application, 1977; 1980 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Annual Reports, 1976-77 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Testimony, Communications Network, Projects, 1973-79 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Programs, 1980-81 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Congressional Hearings, 1973 (Box 42)
      - Resources in Women's Educational Equality, vol., 1-2; 1977-78 (Box 42)
  - United States: Individual states (Box 42)
    - Alabama, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - California: Mills College, 1885; undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Colorado (Box 43)
      - Opportunity School, Denver, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Temple Buell College, 1967; undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Connecticut (Box 43)
      - Ingleside School for Girls, 1894 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - Litchfield Seminary, n.d (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - District of Columbia (Box 43)
      - Mrs. David H. Burr's French and English Seminary for Young Ladies, 1846 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Norwood Femal Institute, 1887 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - School for Colored Girls (Myrtilla Miner), 1854 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Florida: Bethune-Cookman College, Daytona Beach, 1948; undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Georgia (Box 43)
      - Female Seminary, Washington, 1840 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - Spelman College, 1981 (Box 43)
      - Wesleyan College, Macon, 1925-62 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Illinois, 1883-1944 (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Indiana, 1950 (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Iowa, 1855; 1976 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Kentucky: Caney Junior College (later Alice Lloyd College), 1962; undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Maine: Maine Industrial School for Girls, 1898 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Maryland (Box 43)
      - Johns Hopkins University, 1933 (Box 43, Folder 18)
      - Patapsco Female Institute: Natural Philosophy for Schools, Families, and Private Students by A.H. Lincoln Phelps, 1856 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Massachusetts [see separate boxes] (Box 43)
    - Michigan: Univ. of Michigan, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Mississippi, 1934 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Missouri: Washington University, St. Louis, 1867; 1940 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - New Hampshire (Box 43)
      - Adams Female Academy, Derry, 1843 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - Mt. Caesar Seminary, Swanzey Centre (Keene), 1854 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - Tilden Seminary, West Lebanon, NH: The Tilden Enterprise (student newspaper), 1872-80 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - New Jersey (Box 44)
      - Douglass College, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - Evelyn College (Women's College of Princeton Univ.), undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - State Normal School, Trenton, 1856 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - New Mexico: Ramona Indian Girls' School, 1887 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - New York [see separate boxes] (Box 44)
    - North Carolina: Palmer Memorial Institute, 1936-48 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Ohio (Box 44)
      - Case Western Reserve, Adelbert College, Cleveland College, 1884; 1970 (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Granville Female College, Granville, Ohio, 1879 (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Lake Erie Female Seminary, Painesville, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Miss Rice's Home and Day School, 1884 (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Oberlin College, 1882-1955 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Ohio State University, 1897 (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Selina Colbert Huntington: letter, undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Steubenville Female Seminary, 1868; 1869 (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Western Reserve Univ. (College for Women), 1926-57 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Pennsylvania [see separate boxes] (Box 44)
    - Rhode Island, 1896-1957 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Southern States: Southern Women in the recent Educational Movement in the South by Rev. A.D. Mayo, Bureau of Education Circular No., 1; 1892 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Tennessee: Neophogen College; Lincoln Memorial U.; Lebanon Coll., 1877-1917 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Vermont, 1924-73 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Virginia: State Normal School for Women, E. Radford, 1918 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - West Virginia, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Wisconsin: Milwaukee Downer Seminary, 1848; 2001 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Massachusetts (Box 44)
      - General articles, 1856-1904 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - Abbot Female Academy, Andover, 1843-79 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - Bradford Academy, 1839-1930 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - Concord Academy: ?Through Crowded Ways,? by Elizabeth B. Hall, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - Framingham State Normal School: historical sketches, 1914 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - Gilman School, Cambridge, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Greenfield High School for Young Ladies, 1902 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Harvard, 1891-1970 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      - High School for Girls, Boston, 1826 (Box 45, Folder 9)
      - Howard Collegiate Institute, West Bridgewater, 1883 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      - Ipswich Female Seminary, 1831-1903 (Box 45, Folder 11)
      - Ladies Collegiate Institute, Worcester, 1856; 1858 (Box 45, Folder 12)
      - Lasell Female Seminary, Auburndale, 1871-72 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      - MIT: "100 Years of Women at MIT," Conference, June 2-3, 1973 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      - MacDuffie School for Girls, Springfield, 1913; undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Mt. Holyoke College (Box 45)
        - Anniversaries: 75th, 1912; 100th, 1937 (Box 45, Folder 16)
        - Choragos, Vol 5, 12, Feb 17, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 17)
        - Clippings, pamphlets, programs, 1856-1972 (Box 45, Folder 18)
        - Pictures, 1897; undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
        - "Women and Education in America: The Last 150 years,", 1982 (Box 45, Folder 20)
      - Mt. Vernon Female School, 1831 (Box 45, Folder 21)
      - Mt. Washington Boarding and Day School for Young Ladies, So. Boston, 1856 (Box 45, Folder 22)
      - Newburyport: A Forgotten Chapter in American Education: Jane Andrews of Newburyport by Norma Kidd Green, 1961 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Northfield Young Ladies Seminary, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - Northampton (Box 46)
        - Gothic Seminary, 1837 (Box 46, Folder 3)
        - Northampton School for Girls, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - Pine Manor Junior College, 1969 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Pittsfield Young Ladies' Institute, 1844 (Box 46, Folder 6)
      - Powers Institute, Bernardston, 1869 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - Radcliffe [see separate boxes] (Box 46)
      - Simmons College, Boston, 1902; 1959 (Box 46, Folder 8)
      - Smith College: Conference on the History of Women's Higher Education, 1982 [see also College Archives] (Box 46, Folder 9)
      - State Industrial School for Girls, Lancaster, 1856 (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - State Normal School, Salem, 1883-84 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - Tufts University, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - Wellesley College, 1874-1981 (Box 46, Folder 13)
      - Westfield Academy, 1840-52 (Box 46, Folder 14)
      - Wheaton, 1857-1934 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      - Williams College, 1872 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      - Young Ladies High School, Phillips Place, Boston, 1834 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      - Radcliffe College (Box 46)
        - Miscellaneous, 1945-73 (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - History, 1879-1979 (Box 47, Folder 2)
        - Radcliffe Institute for Independent Study, 1961 (Box 47, Folder 3)
        - Radcliffe Magazine, 1910 (Box 47, Folder 4)
        - Radcliffe Quarterly, 1948-50; 1979 (Box 47, Folder 5)
        - Second Century Radcliffe News, June '81 (Box 47, Folder 6)
        - Radcliffe Re-News, 1950 (Box 47, Folder 7)
        - Murray Research Center, 1980; 1981 (Box 47, Folder 8)
        - Radcliffe Seminar, 1951-53 (Box 47, Folder 9-10)
        - ?What We Found at Radcliffe,?, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
        - The Story of Fay House by Christina Hopkinson Baker, 1929 (Box 47)
        - An Acre for Education: Being Notes on the History of Radcliffe College by David McCord, 1958 (Box 47)
        - Graduate Education for Women: The Radcliffe Ph.D., 1956 (Box 47)
        - Radcliffe College by President LeBaron R. Briggs, undated (Box 47)
        - Radcliffe College:, 1879-1929; 1929 (Box 47)
        - "Women: Resource for a Changing World" conference, April 1972 (Box 47)
          - Typescripts: Session I & II and duplicate (Box 48, Folder 1-3)
          - 17 cassettes of sessions (Box 48)
    - New York (Box 48)
      - Albany Female Academy, 1844-63 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Amsterdam Female Seminary, 1839 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Barnard College (Box 49)
        - General, 1924-7 (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - Annie Nathan Meyer, photos, 1884-1954 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      - Brooklyn Female Academy, 1846 [SEE ALSO: books on shelf] (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Columbia College, 1883 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Cornell [see Sage College] (Box 49)
      - Cottage Hill Seminary for Young Ladies, Poughkeepsie, 1866 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Dobbs Ferry Finishing School, circa 1897 [see Oversize materials] (Box 49)
      - Elmira College, 1926-55 (Box 49, Folder 8)
      - Emily Judson Hall, Hamilton, 1895; undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Emma Willard School [see Troy Female Seminary] (Box 49)
      - Free Academy for Females (Report of. Bd. of Ed.), 1849 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - The Masters School, 1977; undated (Box 49, Folder 11)
      - New School for Social Research, undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - New York Collegiate Institute [see separate box] (Box 49)
      - Rutgers, 1839-67 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - Sage College (Cornell), 1873-83 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Sarah Lawrence College, 1935; undated (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - Seward Female Seminary, Rochester, 1839 (Box 49, Folder 16)
      - Troy Female Seminary (Emma Willard School), 1870-98 (Box 49, Folder 17)
      - Utica Female Academy, 1856 (Box 49, Folder 18)
      - Vassar College [see separate box] (Box 49)
      - Wilson Industrial School Association for Girls: Annual reports, 1855; 1857 (Box 49, Folder 19)
      - Wyomanock Female Seminary, New Lebanon, 1870 (Box 49, Folder 20)
      - New York Collegiate Institute (aka Miss Mary Schoonmaker?s School for Girls) (Box 49)
        - General, 1867-1925; undated (Box 50, Folder 1)
        - List of graduates, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 2)
        - Photographs, 1894-1907 (Box 50, Folder 3)
        - Composition notebooks and compositions, Louise Townsend, 1900-07 (Box 50, Folder 4-12)
        - ?My Commencement? scrapbook, Louise Townsend, 1907 (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - Vassar College [see also Oversize materials] (Box 50)
        - Clippings, 1875-1974 (Box 51)
        - Magazine articles, 1890-1951 (Box 51, Folder 1)
        - Pamphlets, 1869-1940 (Box 51, Folder 2)
        - Centennial, 1961 (Box 51, Folder 3)
        - The Great Experiment: A Chronicle of Vassar, 1961 (Box 52)
        - Vassar: A Second Glance, 1942 (Box 52)
        - Vassar College Fiftieth Anniversary, 1915 (Box 52)
        - Verdun Experiences by Margaret Lambie, 1945 (Box 52)
        - Life at Vassar: Seventy-five Years in Pictures, 1940 (Box 52)
        - Letters from Old-Time Vassar: Written by a Student in 1869-70 (1915) (Box 52)
        - The Vassar Miscellany, 50th Anniv. Number, 1915 (Box 52)
        - The Magnificent Enterprise: A Chronicle of Vassar College, compiled by Dorothy A. Plum and George B. Dowell, 1961 (Box 52)
        - The Golden Age of Vassar by Mary Harriott Norris, 1915 (Box 52)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 52)
      - A History of the Rise, Progress, and Present Condition of Bethlehem Female Seminary, 1785-1858 by William C. Reichel, 1858 (Box 53)
      - Bryn Mawr (Box 53)
        - History, 1915-52 (Box 53, Folder 1)
        - 75th Anniversary, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 2)
        - 50th Anniversary, 1935 (Box 53, Folder 3)